The Register to the Betsy Jolas Papers
Yale University Music Library
Betsy Jolas Papers
1926-2010
MSS 106
Yale University Music Library
68
Jolas, Betsy, 1926-
Biographical / Historical
The Franco-American composer Betsy Jolas ranks among the most distinguished and influential modern composers. She was born in Paris in 1926. Her American parents, Eugène and Maria Jolas edited Transition, an important literary journal. Betsy Jolas grew up in a literary environment, and from her childhood she was personally acquainted with many prominent writers, including James Joyce. As war came to France in 1940, the Jolas family moved to New York. Betsy studied at the Lycée Français in New York, and then at Bennington College in Vermont. She studied composition with Paul Boepple, piano with Helen Schnabel, and organ with Carl Weinrich. After the war, she returned to France. She married Gabriel Illouz in 1949; they had three children. At the Paris Conservatoire she studied under Darius Milhaud and Olivier Messiaen, the latter of whom she assisted and then succeeded as professor of analysis (1975) and professor of composition (1978). She has spent most of her career in France, but she retains dual citizenship in France and the United States. She has served as a visiting professor at several American universities, including Yale, and she is a member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters and the American Academy of Arts & Sciences. (She has received many other awards and honors as well.) Jolas has composed numerous instrumental and vocal works in a wide variety of combinations. Her musical style was much influenced by Webern, as well as Boulez and Stockhausen. Her literary background is evident in her exploration of the relationships between words and music. She is the composer of four operas, Le pavillon au bord de la rivière, Le Cyclope, Schliemann, and Iliade l'amour.
Scope and Contents
The Betsy Jolas Papers include music, correspondence, writings, teaching materials, programs, clippings, journals, calendars, photographs, sound recordings, awards and other materials by and about the composer Betsy Jolas. The first series in the collection contains manuscript and printed scores by Jolas and by other composers (1958-2006). Some of Jolas' scores are accompanied by production notes, scenarios, and libretti, and many of the scores she collected contain annotations. The second series contains correspondence (1937-2010), both personal and institutional. Jolas corresponded with notable figures from the American and French Avant-Garde, such as Pierre Boulez, Elliott Carter, Henri Dutilleux, and Darius Milhaud, all of whom are represented in this series. The third series contains teaching materials that Jolas used in her lengthy career as a university instructor. The fourth series, Writings (1963-2009), contains similar material, and also includes a "lesson in poetics" given to a young Jolas in 1940 by James Joyce. Series five (1943-2010) consists of programs for concerts, festivals, and award ceremonies, and Series six (1949-2009) contains related publicity materials and press releases. Series seven contains pocket calendars and personal journals; the latter are restricted until the death of Betsy Jolas. Series eight (1926-2006) includes both professional and personal photos of Jolas and others. Series nine is comprised of degrees earned by Jolas, and awards given to her, including the Legion d'Honneur (1996), and the Ordre National du Mérite (2001). The final series includes sound recordings and media in a variety of formats: test pressings, reel-to-reel tapes, cassettes, CDs, and DVDs. The recordings include a number of performances of Jolas' compositions, as well as interviews and lectures. Note that this series is organized by format.
Related Materials
Researchers may also wish to consult the Eugène and Maria Jolas papers (GEN MSS 108) in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library of Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Access to the journals of Betsy Jolas (Series VII.1), is restricted until her death.
Composers -- France -- 20th Century; Jolas, Betsy, 1926-
- Music, 1958-2006; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into two subseries: Music by Betsy Jolas, and Music by Others. The first subseries, the larger of the two, contains manuscript and printed scores of Jolas's own music. It is organized by genre; works are listed alphabetically within each genre. Materials include but are not limited to: manuscript originals and copies, libretti, scenarios and production notes, performance notes, typescripts and proofs with annotations, and published scores. The first subseries also includes arrangements and transcriptions by Jolas, as well as miscellaneous sketches and songs written for family members. The second subseries comprises published scores by various composers, organized alphabetically by the composer's last name. The majority of the scores contain analytical and historical annotations by Betsy Jolas. Also included are scores that are autographed or dedicated to Jolas.
  - Music by Jolas, 1
    - Opera, 1
      - Le Cyclope, 172 pages; Photocopy of ms. score with annotations in pen and pencil. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Le Cyclope, 93 pages; Typed copies of libretto in English and French, with annotations. Includes correspondence and production notes. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - La Maison qui Chante, 29 pages; Holograph in pencil and photocopy of manuscript. "Title provisiore." (Box 2, Folder 1)
        General
        Standard Title: La Maison qui Chante
      - La Maison qui Chante, 14 pages; Holograph score in pencil. For narrator, soloists, choir, clarinet, bass clarinet, and piano "Version 1." (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - La Maison qui Chante, 15 pages; Sketches in pencil. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Les Voix, Titre provisoire, 10 pages; Color proof of book and 1 pages letter from Leigh Sauerwein. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Les Voix, Titre provisoire, 30 pages; Typed libretti and text with with annotations in pencil and ink. Several copies in French and English. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Le Pavillon au bord de la Riviera, 156 pages; Published libretto in French, with annotations; typewritten libretto in French, with annotations; holograph scenario in pencil; photocopy of libretto, with annotations; published scenario, with annotations; photocopy of article, "Le Dramaturge Chinois Kuan Han Chin"; photocopy of libretto, in English; photocopy of Chinese text; photocopy of published libretto, in English; handwritten notes and dialogue in pencil. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Le Pavillon au bord de la Riviera, 49 pages; Sketches in pen and pencil with annotations, holograph score. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Le Pavillon au bord de la Riviera, 256 pages; Four bound holograph scores and parts with annotations. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Schliemann notes, circa 50 pages; Handwritten notes in pencil; printed score (incomplete). (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Schliemann Act I, circa 160 pages; Handwritten score in pencil with annotations. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Schliemann Act II, circa 160 pages; Handwritten score in pencil with annotations. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Schliemann Act II, scene 2, circa 25 pages; Act II Scene 2, printed orchestral parts with annotations. (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Schliemann Act III, circa 160 pages; Handwritten score in pencil with annotations. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Schliemann libretto notes, circa 80 pages; Handwritten and typed libretto in pencil, with notes and annotations. (Box 2A, Folder 1)
      - Schliemann libretto, 1994; 105 pages; Typed, bound libretto with pencil annotations. (Box 2A, Folder 2)
      - Schliemann libretto, incomplete, 28 pages; Typed libretto with pencil annotations. Incomplete. (Box 2A, Folder 3)
      - Schliemann libretto, circa 80 pages; Acts I, II, III with corrections. Typescript with notes and annotations. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Schliemann libretto, circa 200 pages; Typed libretto (2 copies), with annotations and notes. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Film, radio, and incidental stage music, 2
      - Aimée, 76 pages; Holograph score in pencil. Includes several photocopies and handwritten notes in pencil. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Aventure en Laponie, 28 pages; Holograph manuscript in black pen with annotations in pencil. Stamped: "S.A.C.E.M 10. Rue Chaptal Paris. 22 Juin 1960 – 017143. Films." (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Le Chant de l'amour triomphant, 18 pages; Two complete photocopies and one partial copy of manuscript, with annotations. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Le Chant de l'amour triomphant, 52 pages; Published typescript of radio play with pencil annotations. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Le Chant de l'amour triomphant, 7 pages; Handwritten notes in pencil. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Code génétique, 69 pages; Handwritten notes in pencil; typescript of scene descriptions and corresponding handwritten notes, dated "4.7.67"; photocopies of manuscript with pencil annotations, stamped: "S.A.C.E.M 10 Rue Chaptal Paris. 027055 -- 19 Juil 68. Films." (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Danse et affections rhumatismales, 5 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with pencil and pen annotations. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Dans la chaleur vacante, 74 pages; Includes typed pages of text with pencil annotations, handwritten notes, scenarios, and correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Dans La chaleur vacante, 173 pages; Holograph score in pen with annotations; photocopy of score. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - La Deuxieme existence du camp de Tatenberg d'Armand Gatti, 45 pages; Holograph score in pen with annotations in pencil and pen, dated "1962". Includes several sketches and excerpts from musical movements. Stamped: "Sociéte des Auteurs Compositeurs Editeurs de Musique. 20 Avr 1962 – 774, 608." (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Mozart a Manaus ou Le Royaume des Amazones, by Bruno Bayen and Betsy Jolas., 121 pages; Two typescripts of scenarios and dialogue with handwritten annotations. Includes related correspondence and other materials. Contains no music. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Musique d'accompagnement pour Iphigenie, 19 pages (score + parts); Photocopy of manuscript score with handwritten annotations, dated "Paris 16.12.65". Stamped: "Société des Auteurs Compositeurs Editeurs de Musique. 881946. 13 Juil 66." (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Photo-souvenir, 39 pages; Holograph score in ink with pencil annotations. Includes handwritten notes in pencil. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Poussin d'un jour, 14 pages; Holograph score in ink with pencil annotations. Stamped: "S.A.C.E.M. 22 Juin 1960 – 017142. Films." (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Réeducation eu rhumatologie, 22 pages; Holograph score in ink with annotations in pencil, dated "Paris 9 Mars 1958". Stamped: "S.A.C.E.M. 20 Mar 1958 – 014164. Films." (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Revue des arts – Riopelle, 17 pages; Photocopy of score. Includes several pages of handwritten notes in pencil and other materials. (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - La Tempête, 157 pages; Typescript of scenario with annotations in pen; holograph score in pencil; transparencies of scores and parts. (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Composed for a French TV production of Shakespeare's Tempest, translation by André du Bouchet, directed by François Gir.
      - La Tempête, 1962; 2 pages; Manuscript sketch in pencil with note (includes sketch for Tales of the Summer Sea[?]) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Music for orchestra or large ensemble, 3
      - B Day, 2006; 39 pages; Manuscript score in pencil with program note. (Box 5, Folder 1A)
      - Frauenleben: 9 lieder pour alto et orchestra, 36 pages; Holograph score in pencil. Includes notes. (Box 5, Folder 1B)
      - J. D. E., 3 pages; Holograph score in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - J. D. E.: pour 14 instruments, 39 pages; Holograph in ink and pencil. "Durée: environ 9' 30, crée à La Chaux de Fond (Suisse) le 5. 2. 66 par l'Ensemble du Domaine Musical sous la directions de Gilbert Amy." (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - J. D. E.: pour 14 instruments, 114 pages; Three photocopies of manuscript score with annotations in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Just a minute, 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. "An anniversary piece for the 1986 Colorado Music Festival, Duration: 50" to 1'; Paris June 6 1986." (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Lumor: 7 Lieder spirituels pour saxophone et orchestre, 32 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil; photocopy of manuscript. Includes notes. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Lumor: 7 Lieder spirituels pour saxophone et orchestre, 68 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Commande de Radio France." (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Lumor: 7 Lieder spirituels pour saxophone et orchestra, arr. Alexis Bacon, 20 pages; Computer generated score with annotations in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Musique d'hiver, 82 pages; Two photocopies of manuscript score with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to: Xavier Darasse, "Chérence 11. 8. 71." (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - D'un opera de voyage, 1 page; Photocopy of manuscript sketch. "Original in Mots, sketches" (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - D'un opera de voyage, 40 pages; Holograph in pencil. "1e version (1967), Durée ca 10'." (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - D'un opera de voyage, 39 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - D'un opera de voyage, 40 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - D'un opera de voyage, 6 pages; Sketch of percussion parts. Includes notes. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Onze Lieder: pour trompette en ut et orchestre de chambre, 26 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to Pierre Thibaud, "Paris le 19. 9. 77." Includes 3 pages of sketches. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Petite symphonie concertante: pour violon dirigeant et orchestre, 32 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Paris le 14 11 1996 Dedicated to: Peter Csaba." (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Petite symphonie concertante: pour violon dirigeant et orchestre, 9 pages; Condensed score with indications for instrumentation in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Petite symphonie concertante, 11 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Petite symphonie concertante, Holograph in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Points d'or: pour un saxophoniste et quinze instrument, 74 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "1e version (á choix), Chérence 30. 12. 81". (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Points d'or (Sketches), 5 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Preludes, fanfares, interludes, sonneries, 38 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. Dedicated to Fréderic, "Chérence 26. 6. 83." (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Quatre plages, 20 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Mai 1968." (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Quatre plages: pour orchestre á cordes 8 6 4 4 2, 8 pages; Holograph in ink. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Stances: pour piano et orchestre, 57 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to Claude Helffer, "Chérence le 5 Mars 1978." (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Symphonie pour petit orchestre, 1957; 46 pages; Photocopy of manuscript. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Tales of a summer sea, 1 page; Photocopy of sketch (original filed under "La Tempête") (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Tales of a summer sea: pour orchestre, 41 pages; Published score with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to Gunther Schuller. Commissioned by the Fromm Music Foundation at Harvard for the 1977 Festival of Contemporary Music at Tanglewood. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Tales of a summer sea: pour orchestre, 28 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and ink. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Tales of a summer sea: for orchestra, 34 pages; Holograph in pencil with annotations in colored pencil. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Tales of a summer sea 77, 36 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. Includes notes. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Wanderlied, 2002; 34 pages; Manuscript score in pencil. "Chérence le 21 decembre 2002 (18h30)" (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Wanderlied, 2002; 68 pages; Bound published score with annotations. (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Wanderlied, 2002; 34 pages; Manuscript score for engraving, in pencil. "Chérence le 31 decembre 2002" (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Wanderlied, 2002; 18 pages; Manuscript sketches in ink and pencil. (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Well Met, 1973; 3 pages; Sketches in pencil. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Well Met, 1973; 19 pages; Photocopied score with pencil annotations. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Well Met, 1973-2004; 2 pages; Formation layout for performance, with edits for 2004 performance (within score). Pencil annotations. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Well Met 04, 9 pages; Scenario (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Well Met 04, 10 pages; Scenario sketches and notes in ink and pencil. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Well Met 04, 2004; 73 pages; Photocopy of manuscript score with pencil annotations. "Version 26 07 04" (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Well Met 04, 48 pages; Various sketches in ink and pencil. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Well Met 04, 1973-2004; 73 pages; Manuscript score in pencil. "Chérence le 10 september 2004" (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Chamber music, 4
      - 2 pièces pour clarinette et piano, 9 pages; Holograph in ink. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 2 pièces pour clarinette et piano, 3 pages; Photocopy of movement II, with annotations in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - 4 duos: alto piano, Holograph in pencil. Includes: L'Interdite, La toute-vive, La Grande Irenée. "New Haven 1. 2. 1979." (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - 4 duos, 9 pages; Photocopy of manuscript and published score. Includes: [L'Interdite], La toute-vive, La Grande Irenée. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Ah Haydn, 25 pages; For violin, violoncello, and piano. Holograph in pencil. Includes themes from Haydn's music. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Ah Haydn, 7 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Ah Haydn, 26 pages; Manuscript score in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - L'Ardente: pour alto et piano, 7 pages; "Commande du Conservatoire National Supérieur de Musique, Paris, le 28-12-1978." (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - L'Ardente / Betsy Jolas, 3 pages; Photocopy of first 3 pages of score with annotations. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Come follow, 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Come follow...": pour basson et alto, 4 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Fantaisie à 2: "come follow follow..." pour basson et alto, 7 pages; Holograph in pencil. Dedicated to: Pascal Gallois: basson et Garth Knox: alto. Includes 1 page of "Come follow" by John Hilton. "Création le 20 08 02 Paris Hotel d'Albret." (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Dialogue: pour hautbois et alto, 7 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Dialogue: pour hautbois et alto, 6 pages.; Holograph in ink. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - EA: Petite suite variée pour trompette en ut et vibraphone, 11 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Chérence le 22 Avril 1990, ca 9' 30"." (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - L'Echo, 7 pages; Holograph in pencil. For violin, viola, violoncello, and piano. "Pour Villecroze, Villecroze 21 Juillet 2005." (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Etats: pour violon et six percussions, 24 pages; Holograph in pencil; photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Includes notes. Dedicated to: Gérard Jarry - aux Percussions de Strasbourg. "Paris le 29 Mai 1969." (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Figures I, 5 pages; Holograph in ink. For 2 flutes, violin, and string orchestra. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Figures: suite pour orchestre á cordes et deux flûte, 1950; 7 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in ink and pencil. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Fuguette à 12 sax: pour C La V D E, 2 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in ink. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Fuguette à 12 sax, 2 pages; Computer-generated score. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Invention à 2 voix avec accompagnement à rythme oblige, 4 pages; Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - How now, 15 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. For clarinet, bassoon, horn, 2 violins, viola, violoncello, and bass. "Paris 29. 1. 73, rev. 29. 7. 79." (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - How now, 14 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. "Paris 29. 1. 73." (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Lassus Ricercare, 35 pages; Holograph in ink. For 2 trumpets, 3 trombones, 2 percussionists, harp, 2 pianos, Celesta played by the second pianist. Dedicated to Paul Boepple, "Paris le 17. 12. 70." (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Lassus Ricercare, 35 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Includes Lassus transcriptions. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Lassus Ricercare, 49 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil and pen. Includes holograph transcriptions of Lassus and Josquin des Prez. (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Lassus Ricercare: pour dix instruments, arr. X. Hascher, 1992; 20 pages (score and parts); Holograph in ink with annotations in pencil; photocopy of manuscript with annotations. Includes note. (Box 8, Folder 12)
        Hascher, Xavier
      - Lovemusic, 12 pages; Holograph in pencil. For flute and bass clarinet. Dedicated to Mario Caroli and Armand Angster. "Chérence le 11 Septembre 2005." (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Lovemusic, 13 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Includes notes. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Lovemusic, 9 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Lullaby (1945): for violin and piano, 4 pages; Photocopy of manuscript. (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Menuet-Canon: pour quatre instruments de même register, 1 page; Computer generated score. (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Mouvement pour cinq archets, 4 pages; Holograph in ink. For 2 violins, 2 violas, violoncello. "Paris, le 7 Janvier 1949." (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Music for here, 6 pages; Holograph in pencil. For bassoon with viola and cello accompaniment. "Commissioned by the Norfolk Chamber Music Festival, Yale Summer School of Music; Bennington le 15 Mai 1994." (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Music for Joan, 9 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. For vibraphone and piano; "Paris le 3 Aout 1988." (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Music to go, 3 pages; Holograph in pencil. For viola and violoncello, dedicated to Dominique Troncin. "Paris le 11 Janvier 1995." (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Music to go, 1 page; Holograph in pencil. Includes Schütz arrangements and sketches. (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Musique pour Delphine: pour violon et violoncelle, 1992; 6 pages; Holograph in pencil. "23 Octobre 1992." (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Musique pour Xavier: pour clarinette en si bémol, saxophone ténor, violon, 1993; 7 pages; Holograph in pencil. "Commande du Festival de Charonne; Paris le 24 Avril 1993." (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Musique pour Xavier, 1993; 4 pages; Holograph in pencil. For clarinet, tenor saxophone, and violin; "1e version, fin modifiée, Chérence 18. 4. 93." (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Musique pour Xavier, 2 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - D'un opera de poupée, 84 pages; Holograph score in pencil with annotations; handwritten notes; typed notes and commentary with pencil annotations. (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - O wall: pour quintette à vent, 18 pages; Photocopy of manuscript with annotations in pencil. Dedicated to Serge et Natalie Koussevitsky. "Paris, 29 6 1976." (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - O wall: a puppet opera for wind quintet, 4 pages; Holograph sketches in pencil. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Petite sonnerie de Juin, 1997; 3 pages; Holograph in pencil. For trumpet, French horn, and trombone. (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Petite sonnerie de Juin, 1 page; Photocopy of first pages of manuscript. (Box 8, Folder 18)